Um, well, you guys got KO. I'm sure you
told you all about uh Caleb and how
excited we are. Just uh really proud of
our staff, our coaches, you know, how
hard everybody worked um you know to uh
to make the selection we made tonight
and we're really happy about it and uh
ready to roll.
>> Questions.
What was um your process for analyzing
the medical with Caleb and determining
obviously that he was good to go from
your perspective?
>> Yeah, I mean I think you know we we have
the best doctors in the country if not
the world and um we have complete
confidence in them. Um you know there's
nothing you know without risk in any
player you you select but we feel very
good you know about where Caleb will be
when it's time to uh go to training camp
and um so we're comfortable with the
injury. kind of negotiate or balance
that understanding that he has a high
potential if the injuries aren't a you
know a derailer. Yeah, I mean it's it's
uh it's it's it took a lot of
discussion, you know. I mean, I think
none of this you can just look at in a
vacuum. So, as we're analyzing Caleb and
we're stacking our board, we just stack
the board based on the way we see the
talent and you're you're analyzing
everything and including everything. And
um we just felt really comfortable where
he was on our board and and the board
fell and he was the best player on the
board and we took him and uh it was
pretty easy.
>> Rob, how important did you feel like
just with where the roster was, the
defensive [clears throat] tackle
position was one you guys needed to look
at throughout the course of the draft?
You know, I mean, just number one, it
might not be fair to Flo and his staff,
but he's so good at whoever is in that
room, making the players play to their
potential and uh and put a really good
product on the field. Um, none at all
really. I mean, we we we wanted, you
know, in the ideal world, we needed help
there and it worked out that way. Um, so
didn't feel pressure at all. There's
other players in the draft that we liked
on the defensive line and um just really
really fortunate for us to get who we
thought, you know, was the very very
best player, you know, on the defensive
line in the draft.
>> Rob, with him having the wingspan that
he does and just the the reach on the
line, how [clears throat] much of a
difference does that make getting
someone like that in that room?
>> I mean, I think KO probably talked about
it. His his traits are off the charts.
You know, you just don't you don't find
guys like this. Uh he's got all the
ability in the world. Like I I told him
I don't even think he realizes how good
he can be. And with our coaching staff
and the work that he's gonna be put in,
I think the sky's is the limit, you
know, and um but in this business, it's
day by day. He's got to get healthy.
He's got to go to camp. He's got to earn
a job. He's got all the potential. Um
and I think together with his commitment
and the resources and the coaching we
have, it's going to give him the best
chance to be successful. What was it
like to get on the phone with him and
just share the news with him and his
family?
>> It was exciting. You know, it was
exciting. My my favorite part of the
day, though, was uh I I called an old
friend and mentor and legend, Scott
Studwell, and uh he was kind enough to
meet me for breakfast this morning. And
uh that kind of got my mind, you know,
in the right spot, you know, and I think
in today's world, there's so many
inputs, you know, and there's AI and
there's all these things. and I just sat
down with Stud and we had some coffee
and and breakfast and we talked about
the way it was in the old days and and
we're not trying to over complicate this
and so a shout out to uh to Stud. We
love your brother and uh thanks for your
counsel.
>> What made you reach out to him? Assuming
you reached out to him, what made you do
that?
>> I respect him so much. I mean I I was
going to go through this process for the
first time in my career. I've been in a
lot of draft rooms with with Stud and
he's he's he's amazing at this and uh
just really really respect him and his
opinion and and uh it was just more of a
general conversation but it was very you
know I felt like it really grounded me
and and I was able to pass that on to
our our coaches and and our personnel
staff as well. How did you look at it in
terms of obviously you talked about
Caleb's traits and then the injuries and
so how do you look at that and project
like where the right place to take him
is or where what what the floor of what
you can take him. I mean, there's all
different ideas.
>> You you you stack you stack the players
based on ability,
um how we like them and and then you got
to take into account things like injury,
um off-field character, uh you know, all
these other things that come into play.
And it's it's it's again, it's nothing
none of this happens in a vacuum. We
stack the board and we keep talking
about it and we're weighing all these
things and we we manipulate it around
until we're comfortable um with the way
we have them stacked the impact that
they can have on our team and uh then we
just follow the board.
>> But do you do you think at all about
like would he be there on day two or
would he be there you know on our next
pick or think like was it your analysis
that he was
>> he might have been there you he might
not. You just you just don't know. I
just know, you know, on our board, he
was the best player there when we
selected him and uh we feel outstanding
about, you know, the selection. Um if it
wasn't for the foot, we would have no
chance of seeing them where we picked
them, you know, and so we're looking at
it as an opportunity from that
standpoint to acquire a really unique
talent and um we're we're so fired up.
>> Was there I mean, you sat in as many
drafts as you have. Was there something
about the way Stud went about it that
stood out to you?
>> I mean, Stu was just the most humble
uh celebrity superstar or or whatever.
And uh you know, Stud just had such a
special way about leading people, about
creating conversation, collaboration,
bringing people together, uh valuing
other people's opinion, not thinking
like, you know, with his resume and all
the things he's accomplished in his
scouting history that that he was any
better at this than anybody else. Um,
you know, and and he had core
fundamentals and and and team building
philosophies that that he believed in,
you know, and and and I respect him and
love him as a friend and
I don't know what else to say about my
guy stud.
>> Rob, you you mentioned off-field
character. What have you gathered about
Caleb's off-field character?
>> Uh, excellent. I mean, we're we're
really excited about, you know, I mean,
everybody has some areas probably to
grow in their lives, you know. um all of
us do. Um but we're we think he's a
tremendous human being. He's a really
really good person. He's fun to be
around. Uh he loves football. Um I like
I said before, I think the interesting
thing about him is he doesn't realize
how good of a player he can be. Um and
it's going to be fun to see Flo and
coach Nielsen and the rest of our staff
work with him and uh help him reach that
potential. Was there any consideration
at all or any phone calls moving around
the board a trade or was it just not as
much of a
>> Yeah, I mean there was you know
typically you're you're making like we
we made all the pre-draft phone calls.
We had several conversations during the
draft. Um you know nothing materialized
for us that we felt like you know made
sense and um you know that's part of the
process and ultimately you know we
wanted to take Caleb where we did and
and we're we're thrilled about it.
Great. Thanks everybody.
>> Go T-Wolves.